准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
愚人节
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
小蜗
醒醒  小蜗
Wake up, Gary
我们今天得搬走了
We're moving today
没错
That's right
要离家出走了
We're leaving home
还会变成乡巴佬
We're going to become peasants
没吃的了
No more food
抱歉  小蜗
Sorry, Gary
乡巴佬只吃捣碎的蚌壳
Peasants only eat mashed-up clamshells
愚人节快乐
April fools
给你吧  兄弟
There you go, pal
我好渴
I'm thirsty
实在渴到极点了
This is an extreme thirst
我好累
I'm exhausted
等不及要把饮料全喝光了
I sure can't wait to drink all these drinks
愚人节快乐
April fools
祝我
To me
他是在高兴个什么东西
What's he so happy about?
四月一号
April 1st?
四月一日
愚人节是海绵宝宝最喜欢的节日
April fools' day is SpongeBob's favorite holiday
蟹老板  我今天不能来上班了
Mr. Krabs, I can't come in today
我感染上了很严重的病
I caught something terrible
感染了什么病
What'd you catch?
看到了今天的日历
I caught sight of the calendar
感 染
先等一下  章鱼哥
Hold on, Squidward
我这边有个人要见你
There's someone here to see you
说他是从藤壶湾艺术馆来的
Says he's from the barnacle bay art museum
想给你本月最佳艺术家称号
and he wants to honor you as artist of the month
我已经到了
I have arrived
什么
What?
笑什么笑
What's so funny?
艺术商在哪
Where's the art dealer?
你刚错过他了
You just missed him
是啊  不过他要我们转告你
Yeah, but he told us to tell you
转告我什么
Tell me what?
他要我转告你
He told me to tell you
愚人节快乐
April Fool
很高兴一直以来在这上班
Well, it's been nice working here
谢谢你的照顾  蟹老板
Thanks for everything, Mr. Krabs
章鱼哥  别走
Squidward, wait
把最后一笔工资寄到我信箱  蟹老板
Just send my last check to the P.O. Box, Mr. Krabs
章鱼哥  刚刚那是开玩笑
Squidward, it was just a joke
今天不会再开你玩笑了
No more jokes on you today
我保证
I promise
真的吗
You do?
真的
Sure
还有不少其他人愿意被开玩笑呢
There's lots of other willing participants
对吧  蟹老板
Right, Mr. Krabs?
只要不开我玩笑就行
Well, as long as it's not me
不好意思
Excuse me
能不能请你告诉我叉子在哪
Could you tell me where the forks are?
餐具
就在这  女士
They're right here, lady
可这是勺子
But this is a spoon
愚人节快乐
April Fools
此处点餐
欢迎光临蟹堡王
Welcome to the Krusty Krab
需要什么服务
How may I help you?
好
Yeah
来两份大号薯条跟一份巨无霸蟹黄堡
Give me two large fries and a jumbo krabby patty
那什么东西
What's that?
我什么都没看到
I didn't see anything
刚刚那位哪去了
Where'd that other guy go?
愚人节快乐
April fools
我就在这
I'm right here
真是太逗了
That was pretty good
你在收银台那边干什么
What are you doing behind the counter?
不好意思
Excuse me
能请你帮我在里面加两块冰吗
Can I get a couple ice cubes in here please?
好啊
Sure
两块冰马上来
A couple of ice cubes coming up
拿去吧
Here you go
谢谢
Thanks
愚人节快乐
April fools
你对我饮料做了什么
What did you do to my drink?
我
I
你什么
You what?
你刚刚要我在饮料里加两块冰
You asked for a couple of ice cubes in your drink
我只加了一块
and I only put in one
那可真是好笑
I guess that is pretty funny
是
Yeah
你鞋带松了
Your shoe's untied
愚人节快乐
April fools
你没穿鞋子
You're not wearing shoes
愚人节快乐
April fools
都够了
That's it
海绵宝宝跟他笨得要命的恶作剧
SpongeBob and his stupid pranks
我倒要让他见识什么叫真正的恶作剧
I'm going to show him what a real prank is all about
天啊
Oh, boy
有东西要我去清理
Something for me to clean up
愚人节快乐
April fools
面粉
不
Oh, no
我来接住你  海绵宝宝
I'll catch you, SpongeBob
愚人节快乐
April fools
你这根小腊肠
You little sausage
海绵宝宝  我刚刚是在开玩笑
SpongeBob, I was just kidding
拜托  拜托
Come on, come on
你们都知道我是在开玩笑
You guys know I was just kidding
对吧
Right?
天啊  可怜的孩子
Oh, man, poor kid
他内心一定非常难受
That guy has definitely got some issues to work out
愚人节快乐  混球
April fools, jerk
等等  别走
Wait, don't go
你这个混球
You stink
别走
Wait
那是开玩笑
It was a joke
为什么每次我一高兴就有错
Why is it whenever I'm having fun, it's wrong?
我不是有意害他哭的
I didn't mean to make him cry
看来这就表示最好跟海绵宝宝说
I guess this means I better tell SpongeBob
我很对
I'm sorr
不
ech
看来这就表示最好要道
I guess this means I better apolog
肯定比我想的还要难开口
This is going to be tougher than I thought
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝  出来吧
SpongeBob, come on out
我有事要跟你说
I've got something to tell you
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
SpongeBob
我反思了今天的事
I was thinking about today and
然后就
and, well
好像就是说我可能欠你某种
it just seems that maybe I might owe you some sort of
我平常一般不会这样
this isn't something I normally do
那听清楚了  海绵宝宝
So, so, listen carefully, SpongeBob
因为我要跟你说
because I'm about to tell you
我很
that I'm
什么
What?
派大星  你在这干什么
Patrick, what are you doing here?
挖坑
Digging
你怎么戴着那顶帽子
Why are you wearing that hat?
我不知道
I don't know
海绵宝宝在哪
Where's SpongeBob?
他在家里
He's in the house
心都被打动了
He's impressed
被什么打动了
With what?
不知道
I don't know
一定是什么感人的好事
but it must have been pretty good
才能让他哭成那样吧
to make him cry like that
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
海绵宝宝  让我进去
SpongeBob, let me in there
海绵宝宝  你最好让我进去
SpongeBob, you better let me in there
我可不想使出这招
I don't want to have to use this
你想干什么
What do you want?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我只是想说
I just want to say
我很对不
that I'm soooo
什么
What?
我想说我
I'm trying to say I'm
什么
What?
我只是想说我
I'm just trying to say I'm
肯定有更容易的表达方式
There's got to be an easier way to do this
你不把它打开吗
Well, aren't you going to open it?
打不开
I can't
我没有开瓶器
I don't have a bottle opener
海绵宝宝  我
SpongeBob, I'm
什么
What?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我全部想说的话
all I am trying to say
就是我很
is that I am
对不起
sorry
这就行了
There you go
可我听不
But I couldn't
我不管
I don't care
反正说完了
I said it
我问心无愧
My conscience is clear
一定是感人的好事才能让他哭成那样
Must have been pretty good to make him cry like that
什么
What?
愚人节快乐  混球
April fools, jerk
你这个混球
You stink
妈
Mother?
好了  好了
All right, all right
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry, I'm sorry
我承认  我很对不起
I admit it, I'm sorry
我无意伤害你
I didn't mean to hurt you
其实  海绵宝宝
In fact, SpongeBob
我喜欢你
I like you
我喜欢住在你隔壁
I like living next door
我喜欢你早上特别吵的雾角闹钟
I like your foghorn alarm in the morning
还有你晚上的尖笑声
and your high-pitched giggling at night
我也喜欢小蜗  派大星
I also like Gary, Patrick
珊迪  蟹老板
Sandy, Mr. Krabs
跟所有我迫不得已接触到的其他人
and all of the other people
I'm forced to be in contact with
还有
And
章鱼哥  全都是真心话吗
Squidward, is all that true?
没错  海绵宝宝
Yes, yes, SpongeBob
对  全是真心话
Yes, it's all true
连利马豆跟追车都是真心话吗
Even the part about the lima beans and the car chase?
什么
The what?
对对  随便你
Yes, yes, whatever
但是你一定要跟我保证不跟别人说
but you have to promise not to tell anybody
我保证
I promise
真的吗
Really?
愚人节快乐
April fools
说得对
You're right--
愚人节快乐
April fools
我刚骗了你们所有人
I just fooled you all
没了章鱼哥我们要怎么办
What would we do without Squidward?
海神黄金锅铲
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
客串
配音  海神王
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
厨师博物馆
油脂硬汉
叉子
请看那终极厨具
Behold the ultimate cooking utensil--
黄金锅铲
the golden spatula
海绵宝宝  快看上面写的
Hey, SpongeBob, look what it says here
众多人试图从这远古肥油中
Many have tried to pull this spatula
拔出这把锅铲
from this ancient grease
却无功而返
and all have failed
只有配得上海神王本人的煎炸厨师
"Only a fry cook worthy of King Neptune himself
才能使用
can wield
黄金锅铲
The golden spatula"
帮我跟黄金锅铲合个影
Take a picture of me and the spatula
好  我准备好了
Okay, I'm ready
不好意思
Excuse me
你知道菜单区在哪吗
do you know where the menu section is?
菜单区
The menu section?
这简单
That's easy
就在那边
It's over that way
我的天啊
Holy smokes
没礼貌
Rude
灯光变暗了
The light changed
派大星
Patrick
等一下
Hold on
快拍到了
Almost there
是的  是的
Yes, yes
终于
At last--
能有人配得上皇家厨师的称号了
someone worthy of being the royal fry cook
是谁从肥油里拔出锅铲的
Who has freed the spatula from the grease?
是我  海神王先生
I did, Mr. Neptune, sir
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
真是天大的笑话  小子
A fine jest, boy
你就只是个卑贱的黄色海绵
You are but a lowly yellow sponge
微不足道
Puny
无足轻重
insignificant
平平无奇
a commoner
因此  你无法成为神的煎炸厨师
Therefore, you could never be fry cook to a god and
所以才会成为笑话
this is why it is funny
快到一边去
Now step aside
我要寻找真正的煎炸厨师
while I seek out the true fry cook
不对
No
不对  不是你
No, not you
你太矮了  不对
You're too short, no
热狗
可是
But
美味佳肴的提供者
A purveyor of foods
你一定是我的新任煎炸厨师
Yes, you must be my new fry cook
抱歉  海神王
Sorry, King Neptune
我不负责做  我只负责卖
I don't make them, I just sell them
那是谁把锅铲拔出来的
Then who pulled up the spatula?
是他
Well, he did
这笑话听第二次更好笑了
It is even funnier a second time
你
You, there--
甲壳动物
crustacean
谁  我
Who, me?
你有着擎天神阿特拉斯的体格
You have the physique of Atlas
谢谢
Thanks
我经常健身
I work out
跟我摆姿势
Make poses with me
好
Okay
碰身子
Body slam
是你把锅铲从肥油里拔出来的
You pulled the spatula from the grease
不是我  是海绵宝宝
Nope, that was SpongeBob
玩笑开得过头了
This joke has gone far enough
我的煎炸厨师在哪
Where's my fry cook?
有着如此肥硕身躯的你  想必知道
Certainly you with your prodigious girth would know
谁能做出符合皇家口味的汉堡
who can flip a burger to suit a royal palate
什么
What?
非得要我相信
Am I expected to believe
这个生物就是皇家煎炸厨师的人选吗
this creature is royal fry cook material?
想必你没有任何证据
I don't suppose you have any proof
这东西给本王擦尾鳍都不配
This thing is unfit to even scrub the royal tail fin
并且  从油锅里拔出锅铲还远远不够
And besides, it's not just enough
to pull a spatula off a greasy griddle
煎炸厨师
there are certain
必须要有指定的特点
qualities that a royal fry cook must have
比如
Like?
皇家煎炸厨师必须是
The royal fry cook must be
左撇子
left-handed
其实我两只都是左手
Actually, I've got two
而且皇家煎炸厨师穿
Also, the royal fry cook wears
红色内裤
the red underwear
不对  蓝色
No, blue
皇家煎炸厨师的钱包里有
The royal fry cook's wallet contains
他的大脚趾
his big toes
有六个
He has six
他就是新任皇家煎炸厨师  你得
He is the new royal fry cook and you
安静
Silence
里面是不是很热
Is it hot in here, or what?
派大星
Patrick
你伤到我朋友了
You hurt my friend
你根本就算不上王
You're not a king
你就是个恶霸跟骗子
You're a bully and a liar
那么  小家伙
So, little one
你自以为拥有
You think you have
成为我煎炸厨师的条件
what it takes to be my fry cook
我会证明你有多么一无是处
I will prove your worthlessness
你要通过一项考验
You shall be tested with a challenge
放马过来
Bring it on
海绵宝宝什么考验都能
SpongeBob can handle any
你朋友的傲慢将让你付出惨痛代价
Your friend's arrogance will cost you dearly
你要通过两项考验
There will be two challenges
才两项
Only two?
两项考验哪难得倒海绵宝宝这样的人
What are two challenges to someone like SpongeBob?
三项考验
Three challenges
三项
Three?
三项考验根本没什么
Three challenges are nothing
起码五百项考验还差不多
Might as well be 500 challenges
够了
Enough
将就一项好了
He'll settle for one
只有一项考验
There will be but one challenge
你要跟我对决
you will face me in
终极厨艺擂台赛
the ultimate cook-off
先修好我朋友再接受你考验
I will accept your challenge if you fix my friend
对
Yes
圆家伙
the round one
我会复原他的
I shall restore him
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
SpongeBob
你在这啊
There you are
感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
好得很
Pretty good
你是不是长高了
Say, have you gotten taller?
现在
And now
看看你未来可能的命运
see the fate that may lie ahead
因为  假如有很小的可能
For, if by some minute chance
你成功迎接了考验
you meet the challenge
那么你将会得到丰厚的奖励
your reward will be great
看啊
Behold
不好意思
Woopsie
现在请看
Now behold--
来自亚特兰蒂斯的问候
我挚爱的家  亚特兰蒂斯
my beloved home of Atlantis
堪比太阳神阿波罗的奖赏
A prize worthy of Apollo
你将定居于此神圣之地
You will reside here in this glorious place
只为我下厨
cook only for me
并成为神
and be a god
听着还不错
That sounds pretty good
但是如果你没有成功
But if you should not succeed
你必须放弃煎炸厨师工作
you must give up fry cooking
一辈子
forever
你怎么说
What do you say?
我准备好了
I'm ready
那就好
Very well, then
前往海神波塞殿
To the Poseidome
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen
海神波塞殿
欢迎来到终极厨艺擂台赛
welcome to the ultimate cook-off
好的  先做出一千个汉堡的人获胜
All right, mates first to a thousand patties wins
握手
Shake hands
愿最强者获胜
May the best man win
回到各自的场角
Go back to your corners
铃声一响  开始下厨
and when the bell sounds, come out cooking
你放心  小子
Don't worry, lad
我对你充满信心
I have total confidence in you
赌局
全押海神王赢
Put it all on Neptune
我这水平还不配
I'm not good enough
去亚特兰蒂斯下厨  派大星
to cook in Atlantis, Patrick
我就不该接受这项考验
I never should have taken the challenge
别放弃你的梦想  海绵宝宝
Don't give up your dream, SpongeBob
别人曾经跟我说
People used to tell me
派大星  你一点出息都没有
"Patrick, you'll never amount to anything
你老是异想天开  眼高手低
You'll always have your head in the clouds"
但现在看看我  眼低手高
But just look at me now
一定要加油
Go get 'em, tiger
面包
海神
客队
在很久以前
"Once upon a time"
完美
Perfect
我赢了
I win
手下败将
Loser
免费汉堡大家有份
Free patties for everyone
笨蛋
Fools
你们是没味蕾吗
Have you no taste buds?
这些根本没问题
There's nothing wrong with these
可好吃了
They're delicious
胆小鬼不敢吃自己做的汉堡
Too chicken to eat his own burger
你怎么不吃啊
Why don't you eat it?
自己尝
Try it
快吃
Eat it
好  我汉堡不好吃
Okay, mine's no good
可你们凭什么会觉得他的会比我好
But what makes you think his will be any better?
快给我
Give me that
味道好极了
Why, it tastes so good
我好想再吃一次
I think I'd like to try it a second time
那么
So, uh
你觉得如何
what do you think?
你的汉堡更好
Yours is superior
因此  我向你承认
Therefore, I concede to you--
海绵宝宝  你获胜了
SpongeBob SquarePants, you win
我们要去亚特兰蒂斯
We're going to Atlantis
有什么好笑的
What's so funny?
你  海绵宝宝
You, SpongeBob
要让那个讨厌的东西进宫
That repulsive thing in my palace?
你是说派大星不能跟着来吗
You mean Patrick can't come?
当然不能
Of course not
还有我的朋友们
And my friends
亲爱的小子  你唯一需要的朋友
The only friend you'll need, my dear boy
就是皇家烤架
is the royal grill
真高兴认识你  兄弟
It was nice knowing you, buddy
我知道  蟹老板
I know, Mr. Krabs
我也会想你的
I'll miss you, too
全都赌输了
I lost me bet
来吧  海绵宝宝
Come, SpongeBob
拿好行李
grab your things
是时候启程
It's time to depart
前往亚特兰蒂斯
to Atlantis
我
I
我不想去
I don't want to go
太晚了
It's too late now
没有你的汉堡我无法生活
I can't live without your burgers
你将成为神  喜欢上神的生活
You're going to be a god and like it
可能的确是有个问题
Maybe we do have a problem
慢着  海神王
Wait, Neptune
我有另外一个办法
I have another idea
蟹堡王
早安  蟹堡王的员工们
Good morning, Krusty crew
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
想来点什么
What'll you have?
能先失陪一下吗
Can you excuse me?
该死的炉子烫到了我的手指
The accursed stove has burnt my finger
感受你自己的怒火吧  炉子
Feel thine own wrath, stove
我是怎么跟你交代
What did I tell you
使用法力的事呢  实习生
about using your powers, trainee?
完美的汉堡是用爱做的  不是魔法
Perfect patties are made with love, not magic